That child Would you like to stay overnight?
그 아이를 하룻밤 사시겠다고요?
you are the boss
네가 사장이구나
I can't talk to this bitch.
이년하고는 말이 안 통해서 말이야
You are fluent in Korean.
조선말이 능하시네요
Joseon With girls
조선 계집들하고
I've been in a lot of relationships
연애를 많이 했거든
I'm going to do this today
오늘은 이거랑 할 거고
I am not a prostitute who sells my body.
몸 파는 창기가 아닙니다
They are entertainers.
예인들이지요
If I say I live
내가 산다고 하면
You guys sell art too
너희들은 예술도 팔고
Selling your body too
몸도 파는 거야
What if you don’t want to sell it?
팔지 않겠다면요?
There's going to be a hole in this bitch's head.
이 계집 대가리에 구멍이 나겠지
How about me?
저는 어떠십니까?
The reason you embrace me instead of that child is
그 아이 대신 절 품어 보시는 건
Oh, great.
오, 대단해
How much are you worth?
넌 얼마짜리냐?
It's even free
심지어 공짜랍니다
You're an easy girl.
쉬운 계집이구나
Take it off too
마저 벗겨 봐라
There is one condition
조건이 하나 있습니다
Conditions?
조건?
If you compete for alcohol with me and win,
저와 술을 겨루어 이기시면
Do what you want with this bitch.
이년을 마음대로 하십시오
What a fun bitch.
재밌는 년이네
If I win, I'll have you
내가 이기면 널 갖고
I will have this wrist too
이 손목도 가질 것이다
- That's what you do. - instead
- 그리 하시지요 - 대신
I will make the rules
규칙은 내가 정할 것이다
Hey, eat it slowly
아유, 천천히 좀 먹어
um
음
You too have a lot of events, huh?
너도 참 파란만장하다, 어?
How long has it been since I came here? Conscription, employment, and even robbery?
여기 온 지 얼마나 됐다고 징용에, 취직에, 강도까지?
Please buy me just one gun
총 한 자루만 사 주세요
What's going on? If it's a gun, the kid will tremble
웬일이냐? 총이라면 벌벌 떠는 애가
I will fight for independence
저 독립운동할 겁니다
we are
우리는
The times we live in On a mission to protect
우리가 사는 시대를 지키라는 임무를 받고
You came here
여기 온 거야
Grab the red and white mask and find the guardian stone. return safely
홍백탈을 잡고 수호석을 찾아서 무사히 돌아간다
that's our mission
그게 우리 임무야
- Still... - If you want to join the independence movement
- 그래도... - 독립운동할 거면
thinking of going back home don't do it
집으로 돌아갈 생각 하지 말고
Stay here until the end and take responsibility
여기 끝까지 남아서 책임져
humans of this era It's something you risk your life for.
이 시대 인간들 피 같은 목숨 걸고 하는 일이야
Can we really go back?
우리 진짜 돌아갈 수 있는 거죠?
I have to go
가야지
There's no wifi here
여기는 와이파이도 없잖아
No mint chocolate
민트초코도 없고
We don't even have Jia.
우리 지아도 없고
Instead, there is Lee Rang.
대신 이랑 님이 있죠
Hey, as soon as I got here I saw the kid dying
야, 나 여기 오자마자 애 죽어 가는 것부터 봤어
I thought my heart was going to explode?
아주 심장이 터지는 줄 알았다니까?
You saved me
살리셨잖아요
I hope you can get along better without me
나 없이도 좀 잘 지냈으면 좋겠는데
Like the leader of that bandit group. and sat down
저 마적단 두목 같은 거나 하고 앉았고
Hey, I'm walking a long way I don't know if I'm going to fall
에휴, 내가 발길이 떨어지려나 모르겠다
When are you going to speak?
언제 말씀하실 거예요?
what?
뭐라고?
Well, in a month Suddenly disappear?
뭐, 나 한 달 되면 뿅 하고 사라진다고?
Oh, you too
아, 이랑 님도
I need to give myself time to accept the breakup.
이별을 받아들일 시간을 줘야죠
Oh, what's going on?
아, 이게 무슨 일이야?
Eat, eat, eat, uh
먹어, 먹어, 먹고 있어, 어
What should I do?
어떡해?
- Ugh, what is it? - Ranga
- 어휴, 뭐야? - 랑아
Langa
랑아
Get started!
시작해!
Oh, what should I do?
아, 어떡해?
Oh, I'm going to die like that.
아휴, 저러다 죽겠어요
Pathetic guy
한심한 놈
It's okay, it's okay
괜찮아요, 괜찮습니다
Bring a jar
항아리 가져와
Hey, get the jar.
어이, 항아리 가져와
Yes, that’s Ryu Hong-ju.
그래, 저래야 류홍주지
But where did this guy go? Langa
근데 이 새끼 어디 갔어? 랑아
Langa
랑아
It's because these people are so dishonest
이리들 비실비실해서야
How can you properly function as an in-house employee?
어디 사내 구실은 제대로 하겠습니까?
How dare lowly gisaeng bitches...
천한 기생 년들이 감히...
It's broken
망가졌네
Can you give me that?
저거 나 줄래?
Who are you?
누구야, 너?
You like gayageum, right?
가야금 좋아하시죠?
You're alive.
살아 있구나
You in this era
이 시대의 넌
I'm alive like this
이렇게 살아 있어
Brother, you never give up
형은 너 절대 포기 안 해
who am i The answer is also contained here
내가 누구인지 그 답도 이 안에 들어 있어
Lee Yeon-i
이연이되
It's not a coincidence
이연이 아니다
So what is it?
그럼 뭐지?
♪ Will I understand this feeling someday ♪
♪ 언젠가 이 마음 알까 ♪
♪ Moonlight over the endless sea ♪
♪ 끝이 보이지 않는 바다 위 달빛 ♪
♪ If it shines on me ♪
♪ 내게 비춰 오면 ♪
♪ Will you come ♪
♪ 그대가 올까 ♪
♪ A dream of being there to meet you day and night ♪
♪ 낮밤 없이 마중 나가 있는 꿈 ♪
♪ It doesn't matter where ♪
♪ 어디인지는 상관없어 ♪
♪ The place where my toes touch is my destiny ♪
♪ 이 발끝이 닿는 곳이 나의 운명 ♪
- ♪ I believe, my love ♪ - Mermaid?
- ♪ 난 믿어, 내 사랑 ♪ - 인어?
I'll teach you how to tie it.
매는 법 알려 드릴게요
♪ Become a star Fill up this night ♪
♪ 별이 되어 이 밤을 가득 채워 줘 ♪
This is the club Are you a circus troupe?
여기가 클럽이야 서커스단이야?
I'll have to touch it to see if it's real or not.
진짜인지 아닌지 내가 만져 봐야겠다
be quiet
조용히 좀 해라
Are you really a mermaid? you
진짜 인어지? 너
I'm mixed race
혼혈이야
father is a human fisherman
아버지가 인간 어부
What are you doing in the human world?
인간 세계에서 뭐 하냐?
To become a singer
가수가 되려고
Become a singer
가수가 되든
Whether it's a spectacle or not
구경거리가 되든
Do one of the two
둘 중에 하나만 해
glutinous rice cake
찹쌀떡
Wait a minute
잠깐만
These are my scales
내 비늘이야
If you ever need me...
혹시라도 내가 필요하면...
no need
필요 없어
take it
가져가
I don't need it
필요 없다니까
hello
안녕
The tie looks good on you
넥타이 잘 어울려
Why did you do that?
왜 그러셨어요?
Because of things like me
저 같은 것 때문에
I originally wanted the world There are only two distinctions
난 원래 세상을 딱 두 가지로만 구분하거든
Are you on my side or not?
내 편이냐, 아니냐
Either risk your life to protect it or
목숨 걸고 지키거나
Risk your life and throw it away
목숨 걸고 발라 버려
This is my first time as a boss.
사장님이 처음이에요
The person who treated the gisaeng like people
기생들 사람처럼 대우해 주신 분이
Did you cry earlier?
아까 울었니?
I didn't cry until the end
안 울었어요, 끝까지
Because the boss taught me that.
사장님이 그렇게 가르쳤으니까요
Well done
잘했다
Are you full?
배부르시죠?
I'm full
배부르긴
I just drank alcohol without any snacks. I feel empty, man.
안주 없이 술만 퍼먹었더니 속이 허하다, 야
Would you like to bake some?
너비아니 좀 구워 올까요?
What time is it and I still haven’t come in? Really, shit
시간이 몇 시인데 아직도 안 들어와 정말, 쯧
Oh, this bastard, really.
아, 이 새끼, 진짜
Aren’t you sleeping?
안 자냐?
Where have you been and what have you been doing?
너 어디서 뭐 하다 왔어?
I drank alcohol, why?
술 마셨다, 왜?
You have a 10 o’clock curfew from now on.
너 이제부터 통금 10시야
crazy guy
미친놈
i don't trust you
나는 너 안 믿어
Who are you?
누구냐?
You are the gatekeeper of this place.
이곳의 문지기시군요
You smell bloody.
너에게서 피비린내가 난다
Descendants of Baekdu Mountain tigers
백두산 호랑이의 자손이
How can you covet a wrong place?
어찌 삿된 곳을 탐하느냐?
It is said that this body is corrupted.
이몸이 삿된 자라 그러합니다
go back
돌아가라
What's in that back case
저 뒤주 안에 든 건
There is only one and only one
오직 원과 한뿐이니
What's inside me
내 속에 든 것도
It's like
그것과 같습니다
It is a seal that cannot be broken for 500 years.
500년 동안 풀리지 않는 봉인이다
today
오늘
It will be solved
풀릴 겁니다
Let's do this.
이쯤 하시죠
I left the scorched rice at home without it. I have to go quickly.
집에 누룽지 안쳐 놓고 와서 빨리 가 봐야 되거든요
Hit it!
쳐라!
It's fire
불이야
Poor thing
가여운 것
Now
자
Go show Lee Yeon your pretty eyes
가서 이연한테 네 예쁜 눈을 보여 줘
What do you want?
원하는 게 뭔데?
this?
이거?
It seems like a valuable item.
소중한 물건인가 보네
Where are you?
어디야?
I found it
찾았다
look at me
나를 봐
Why did you do that? Why did you break your promise? why!
왜 그랬어? 왜 약속을 어겼어? 왜!
What's going on?
무슨 일이에요?
There's someone in the room
방에 누가 있어
Huh? There's nothing?
어? 아무것도 없는데?
You weren't dreaming?
꿈꾸신 거 아니에요?
There was definitely someone there!
분명히 누가 있었다니까!
What is it? who?
뭐가요? 누가?
I don't know
몰라
I don't know what it is
뭔진 모르겠는데
I feel like I've seen something I shouldn't have seen
보면 안 되는 걸 봐 버린 기분이야
Who is this?
이게 누구실까?
Ah, master, why are you here?
아, 주인님이 왜 여기 계세요?
'Cause I'm the boss here
내가 여기 사장이니까
Uh, somehow, uh, for now
어, 어쩐지, 어, 일단
My dreams were a bit disturbing last night.
어저께 꿈자리가 좀 뒤숭숭했어
How dare you run away from me Are you crawling under Lee Yeon?
감히 나한테 도망쳐서 이연 밑으로 기어들어 가?
You tried to kill me
저 죽이려고 하셨잖아요
What happens if I catch my eye?
내 눈에 띄면 어떻게 된다고?
Come here, Gusinju!
이리 와, 구신주!
I hate it
싫어
Is everything that comes into my forest mine?
내 숲에 들어온 거 다 내 건데?
Gusinju
구신주
remember clearly
똑똑히 기억해라
Next time you see me
다음에 내 눈에 띄면
At least you won't be able to use your limbs.
최소한 팔다리는 못 쓰게 될 거다
Please save me
살려 주세요
Let's get hit first
일단 처맞자
No! no!
안 돼! 안 돼!
Shinjuya
신주야
Lee Yeon...
이연...
- Hey, I... - Nice to meet you, Shinju.
- 야, 저... - 반갑다, 신주야
Has it become cuter?
더 귀여워졌네?
Do you two know each other?
둘이 아는 사이야?
That's right
맞다
eat more
더 먹어
I don't like it, I'm full
싫어, 배불러
Ah, this guy, this Just by looking at it, you can see that it is corrupt and corrupt.
아, 이 자식, 이거 딱 봐도 비리비리해 가지고
Eat more, you need to gain weight
더 먹어, 너 살 좀 쪄야 돼
Who are you to say this or that?
네가 뭔데 이래라저래라야?
If you keep not listening to me like this
너 자꾸 이렇게 말 안 들으면
What? What are you going to do?
뭐? 어쩔 건데?
boom, airplane
부웅, 비행기
kid, crazy
아이, 미친
So hurry up and eat
그러니까 얼른 밥 먹어
Baby
자기야
I'll go out and come back
나 나갔다 올게
Oh, that's a disease too
아휴, 저것도 병이다
Hey, aren’t you looking for a red and white mask?
야, 너 홍백탈 안 찾냐?
fool
바보
Did you find him?
찾았어, 그놈?
well
글쎄
I can watch you do it and teach you.
너 하는 거 봐서 가르쳐 줄 수도 있고
Boy, really, hey
아이, 진짜, 야
I'm a bit busy right now
지금은 내가 좀 바빠서
What do you mean you found it?
찾았다는 거야, 뭐야?
Who knows? Inside there
누가 알겠냐? 저 속을
I was curious about this before
전부터 궁금했는데
you with that crazy girl What exactly is it between you?
너 저 미친 여자랑 정확히 무슨 사이냐?
let's swear
맹세하자
no matter what happens to us Let's protect each other
우리 무슨 일이 있어도 서로를 지켜 주기로
Are you sure we will become mountain gods and meet again?
꼭 산신이 돼서 다시 모이는 거다?
Hey, Cheon Muyoung!
야, 천무영!
promise
약속
Oh, what?
아, 뭐냐고?
Just like a broken oath
그냥, 깨져 버린 맹세 같은 거
Eat, eat
먹어, 먹어
Someone wants to meet me urgently?
누가 급히 좀 만나 뵙자는데요?
who?
누가?
Ta-da
짜잔
What kind of flower is this?
웬 꽃이야?
um
음
Is it your favorite flower?
네가 제일 좋아하는 꽃이니까?
I remember that too
그런 것도 기억하고
That's the Chun Mooyoung I knew.
내가 알던 천무영 맞네
I have a bundle of questions
궁금한 게 한 보따리야
You, the grandmother of the undressing group, He died at the seat of the mountain god of the north.
탈의파 할멈이 널 북쪽 산신 자리에서 폐하고
I heard a rumor that it was made of stone
돌로 만들었다는 소문은 들었어
It's true
사실이야
Grandma is among us I thought you were the prettiest
할멈은 우리 중에 널 제일 예뻐했잖아
Why?
대체 왜?
For doing something worth it
그럴 만한 짓을 해서
So until now
그럼 지금까지
For hundreds of years?
수백 년 동안?
I was trapped like a stone
돌이 돼서 갇혀 있었지
I endured it while thinking of you?
나 네 생각 하면서 버텼다?
Our beautiful Hongju
우리 고운 홍주
Just as I hoped
바라던 대로
With my seven younger brother owls, Oh, I hope you'll be living well
일곱이나 되는 동생 부엉이들하고 오순도순 잘 살고 있겠거니
you don't know
넌 모르겠구나
my parents and my younger siblings
우리 부모랑 내 동생들
We all starved to death.
싹 다 굶어 죽었잖아
I went home and found the body.
집에 갔더니 시체더라고
Become a mountain god to me They made such a fuss about me telling me to raise the family.
나한테 꼭 산신이 돼서 집안 일으키라고 그리 들볶더니
When incompetent and weak parents are even good,
무능하고 약한 부모가 착하기까지 하면
I can't even protect my babies.
제 새끼들도 못 지키는 법이지
sorry
미안
I couldn't be your friend and stay by your side.
친구가 돼서 옆에 있어 주지도 못했네
There's nothing to be sorry about
미안할 건 없고
Let me ask you just one question
하나만 묻자
Lee Yeon and you
너랑 이연
What happened?
무슨 일이 있었던 거니?
You couldn't even kill a single ant baby
뭘 어쨌길래 개미 새끼 한 마리도 못 죽이던 네가
Cut open his brother's stomach?
걔 동생 배를 갈라?
the pain I felt
내가 느낀 고통을
I hope Yeon feels the same way
연이가 똑같이 느꼈으면 해서
Like I lost my only brother
내가 하나뿐인 형을 잃었던 것처럼
What are you talking about?
무슨 소리야?
Yeon is coming
연이가 오고 있어
They say your identity is a secret
네 정체 비밀이라며
There's something I want to check
확인해 보고 싶은 게 있어서
Someone looked at me in a hurry and said it was you?
누가 급하게 보자 그러더니 너였냐?
Well, just like that before, he left.
아까는 뭐, 그냥 그러고 가더니
What's with the flowers that don't look good, huh?
안 어울리게 꽃은 또 뭐냐, 어?
what?
뭐야?
It suddenly got dark
갑자기 어두워졌어
What are you doing now?
뭐 하는 거야, 지금?
Hongjoo
홍주야
Hongju, where are you?
홍주야, 어디 있어?
Why is it like that?
왜 저래?
Yuna
연아
Yuna, why are you doing this? are you okay?
연아, 왜 그래? 괜찮아?
Hongjoo
홍주야
Why am I like this, why am I like this?
나 왜 이래, 나 왜 이래?
what's the matter?
왜 그래?
What's going on?
무슨 일 있어?
who is there
누가 있네
Who?
누구?
flower seller
꽃 장수
Hongjoo
홍주야
Why am I doing this, huh?
나 왜 이러는 거야, 어?
Let's go, I'll take you home
가자, 바래다줄게
still you
여전히 넌
You have Lee Yeon in your heart.
이연을 마음에 품고 있구나
Even then
그때도
Even now
지금도
Did you check it for no reason?
괜히 확인했나?
my eyes
내 눈
-What's wrong with my eyes? - Lee Yeon
- 내 눈 왜 이래? - 이연 님
Take a deep breath
심호흡하시고
Open your eyes
눈 떠 보세요
What do you see?
뭐가 보여요?
no
아니
I can't see it
안 보여
Please give me some light
불 좀 주세요
I'll check the pupil reaction.
동공 반응 확인할게요
yes
예
There's no response
반응이 없네요
What are you talking about?
무슨 소리야?
say!
말해!
I think you've lost your eyesight
시력을 잃으신 것 같아요
look at me
나를 봐
That girl last night
어젯밤 그 여자애
Yes?
예?
It's him
그놈이야
It started when I made eye contact with him.
그놈 눈을 마주치고 시작된 거야
What are those drops?
그 방울은 뭐야?
I gave it to you
줬어
I did a good thing
착한 일 했다고
Were you originally human?
원래 인간이었어?
My name, find my name
내 이름, 내 이름을 찾아 줘
Name?
이름?
What does that matter?
그딴 게 뭐가 중요해?
You are so special right now
너 지금 이렇게 특별한데
No! The nine-tailed fox knows
아니야! 구미호는 알고 있어
- What? - What are you doing?
- 뭐? - 너 뭐 하자는 거야?
Don't look!
보지 마!
You can't make eye contact
눈 마주치면 안 돼
What is that kid?
그 꼬마는 뭐고
I'm Saetani
나는 새타니야
Saetani?
새타니?
A monster created by evil consciousness
염매 의식이 만들어낸 괴물
It's in
들어가 있어
Are you crazy?
너 미쳤구나?
That cursed monster I released it to the world
저런 저주받은 괴물을 세상에 풀어 놨어
What about Yeon?
연이는?
Are you suffering?
괴로워하니?
Are you struggling in the dark?
어둠 속에서 몸부림치고 있어?
Is this what you want?
네가 원하는 게 이런 거니?
It was Lee Yeon who broke her oath. I need to be punished
맹세를 어긴 건 이연이야 벌을 받아야지
Oath?
맹세?
Let's protect each other even if we die The three of us swore
죽어도 서로를 지키자고 셋이 맹세해 놓고
One guy fell in love with a human woman. Throw away your place as a mountain god
한 놈은 인간 여자한테 반해서 산신 자리도 내팽개쳐
The other guy
다른 한 놈은
What did you do to raise me like a parent? They say it turned into stone in the hands of the undressing group.
뭔 짓을 했길래 부모처럼 길러 준 탈의파 손에 돌이 돼 버렸대
There was no one next to me
내 옆엔 아무도 없었어
I needed you guys
난 너희들이 필요했는데
-Hong Joo-ya - Just now
- 홍주야 - 이제 겨우
The three of us finally got together again
겨우 우리 셋이 다시 모였는데
Why are you like this?
왜 이따위냐?
come to me
나한테 와
whatever you want
네가 원하는 게 뭐든
I'll give it to you
내가 줄게
Because you never know
혹시 모르니까
Please minimize eye irritation
눈의 자극을 최소화해 주세요
What is that girl?
그 여자애 정체가 뭘까?
I don’t know who it is, but
정체는 모르지만
It's a type of curse that's quite powerful.
꽤 강력한 저주의 일종이에요
Just looking at it puts a curse on you?
보는 것만으로도 저주를 건다고?
I've never heard of such a monster.
그런 요괴는 들어본 적이 없는데
That's not the problem
문제는 그게 아니야
in 1938
1938년에
To the exact address of Myoyeonggak
정확히 묘연각 주소로
The one who will deliver the curse to me How many?
나한테 저주를 배달시킬 놈이 몇이나 될까?
red and white mask
홍백탈
Shinjuya
신주야
fix it
고쳐 줘
I don't have time to be like this
이러고 있을 시간이 없어
I'll find a way
방법 찾아볼게요
Please feed me the porridge first, I need to cheer up.
죽부터 먹여 주세요, 기운 차리셔야 돼
You still hate me, right?
너 아직도 나 싫지?
Because of my greed I held it next to me
내 욕심 때문에 옆에 잡아 두긴 했는데
Why am I doing this to you? I'm confused about whether I can trust it or not
대체 너한테 왜 이러는지 믿을 수는 있는지 헷갈리고
I've been by your side these past few days Are my watching eyes just an ornament?
요 며칠 네 옆에 붙어서 지켜본 내 눈은 장식품이겠냐?
You are not the Lee Yeon I know
넌 내가 아는 이연이 아니야
That's the only reason I kept you alive
그게 널 살려 둔 유일한 이유고
no
아니
you needed a family
넌 가족이 필요했던 거야
Whether I'm real or fake
내가 진짜든 가짜든 간에
Shut up
닥쳐
I can kill you if I want to right here and now
마음만 먹으면 죽일 수도 있어 지금 이 자리에서
While living
살면서
These guys are real monsters Have you met a lot?
진짜 괴물 같은 놈들 많이 만나 봤거든?
I almost died several times
몇 번씩 죽을 뻔한 적도 있고
I've never been scared
한 번도 무서웠던 적이 없는데
It's a little scary now
지금은 좀 무섭다
Scary?
무섭다고?
No one can protect you like this.
이 꼴로는 아무도 못 지켜 주잖아
No matter what happens to you
너한테 무슨 일이 생겨도
Now don't pretend to be my older brother.
이제 와서 형 노릇 하는 척하지 마
No matter what anyone says, I'm your older brother
누가 뭐래도 난 네 형이야
I fed you, clothed you, raised you.
먹이고 입히고, 내가 너 키웠어
so what
그래서 뭐
Are you asking me to return the favor?
나보고 은혜라도 갚으라고?
Give it to me, I'll eat it.
줘, 내가 먹을게
Hey, here
야, 여기
Wow, it’s so ugly I can’t see it.
아유, 꼴사나워서 못 보겠네
Ugh, hey, give it to me
어휴, 야, 줘 봐
- Ah
- 아
Ugh
에휴
- Again
- 또
Baby, feed me kindly, I'm a patient.
아이, 좀 친절히 먹여, 나 환자야
Ah
아
Are you done?
됐냐?
Hey, hey, it tastes bad.
아이씨, 야, 맛없어
Next time, bring mung bean porridge.
다음엔 녹두죽으로 가져와
Oh, what, are there all these guys?
아이, 뭐, 이런 놈이 다 있어?
Where are you going with that body?
그 몸으로 어디를 나가?
The guy in the red and white mask will come
홍백탈 그놈이 올 거야
What are you doing?
얼씨구
think about it
생각해 봐라
I can't see
내가 눈이 안 보여
Would you miss this opportunity?
너라면 이 기회 놓치겠냐?
I can't see it, so what can I do?
안 보이는데 뭐 어쩔 건데?
I should try something
뭐라도 해 봐야지
Even if you walk by yourself
스스로 걷는 거라도
IC
아이씨
Wait a minute
잠깐
stand there
거기 서
five steps to the left
왼쪽으로 다섯 걸음
one, two
하나, 둘
- three, four, five - there
- 셋, 넷, 다섯 - 거기
right there
거기서 오른쪽
- IC - Oh, that's a flower bed, you idiot.
- 아이씨 - 아, 그건 화단이잖아, 멍청아
uh
어
flower bed
화단
nine
아홉
heat
열
seventeen
열일곱
17 steps from the flower bed
화단에서부터 17걸음
What is this?
이게 뭐야?
It’s Gangjeong, eat it.
강정이야, 먹어
Gangjeong?
강정?
Hey, what is it? Why does it smell like this?
아이씨, 뭐야? 냄새가 왜 이래?
dog poop
개똥
Hey, you crazy guy, really.
야, 이 미친놈아, 진짜
Sure, Mr.
확, 씨
Where are you?
어디 있어?
You get caught, you just get caught
너 잡히, 잡히기만 해
Huh?
어?
- hey - IC
- 야 - 아이씨
You, Mr. Lee
너, 이씨
I never thought you would be so excited
저렇게 신나실 줄이야
- One more time? Now, here, here - Where are you?
- 한 번 더? 자, 자, 여기 - 어디야?
That Tawara show
저 타와라 쇼
And my wife, Seiko, a native noblewoman.
그리고 본토 귀족인 제 아내 세이코
Today my wife and I
오늘 우리 부부는
Dedicating two airplanes to the Emperor
두 대의 비행기를 황군에게 헌납하며
My heart becomes bigger
가슴이 웅장해집니다
Peace for 24 million subjects
2,400만 신민의 평화는
Only with the brave emperor
오로지 용감한 황군과
It is thanks to His Majesty the Emperor!
천황 폐하의 덕입니다!
how is it?
어때요?
I'm going to give a speech later when I receive the medal.
이따 이이 훈장 받을 때 연설할 건데
Sounds good?
좋은데요?
at the end
마지막에
Long live His Majesty the Emperor
천황 폐하 만세
Long live the Empire of Japan!
대일본 제국 만세!
What if you put ?
를 넣으면 어떨까요?
yes People who listen are patriotic
그래 듣는 사람들 애국심이
So that it just springs up on its own, right?
저절로 막 솟구치도록 말이지?
Sore
헌데
How much does it cost for two patriotic flags?
애국기 두 대면 얼마입니까?
100,000 won
10만 원
His Excellency the Governor is calling
총독 각하께서 부르십니다
Can you straighten your face?
얼굴 좀 펴지?
Such a glorious day
이렇게 영광스러운 날
If anyone sees
누가 보면
I thought it was an independence movement or something.
독립운동이라도 하는 줄 알겠어
Receiving a medal from the Emperor of Japan I am Tawara Sho's only daughter.
저 일본 천황께 훈장 받는 다와라 쇼의 외동딸이에요
If anyone hears it
누가 들으면
You think your brother-in-law is crazy, right?
형부가 미친놈인 줄 알죠?
There are times when my sister-in-law is this sharp.
난 처제가 이렇게 뾰족할 때가
It was really attractive
참 매력 있더라
Look into it often
종종 들여다봐
With that smooth face
저 반반한 얼굴로
What are you doing?
무슨 짓을 하고 다니는지
You have guessed it, right?
짐작은 하고 계시지 않습니까?
pretending to be human To swallow up this Joseon
인간 행세를 하고 이 조선을 집어삼키려면
i need this family
난 이 가문이 필요하다
my cute new bride
내 귀여운 새 신부는
I hope there isn't a speck of dust
한 점 티끌이 없었으면 하고
- Open your arms. - child
- 팔 벌려 봐 - 아이
Now
자
What is it?
뭐야?
IC
아이씨
Hey, you crazy idiot, do you really want to die?
아이, 미친놈아, 너 진짜 죽을래?
Let’s ward off evil.
액막이를 하시죠
Huh?
어?
Exorcism? Is that okay?
액막이? 그걸로 되겠어?
Well, it's a traditional method, but it's acceptable. All curses can be removed
뭐, 전통적인 방법이지만 웬만한 저주는 다 떼어 낼 수 있을 거예요
Please take off the blindfold. I need something from my body
안대 좀 풀어 주세요 몸에 지녔던 물건이 필요해요
uh
어
I'll be back soon
금방 갔다 올게요
Be careful
조심히 다녀와
Ah, Mr.
아, 씨
Oh, grapes?
아, 포도?
When I think about my childhood I still smell grapes
어린 시절을 생각하면 아직도 포도 냄새가 나
Wow, that damn bow
어유, 그놈의 절
The grapes are ripening so hard He was a winemaker
지긋지긋하게 포도가 열려서 포도사였지
It's our hometown
우리한텐 고향이자
It was an orphanage
고아원이었어
What is that mountain god?
그깟 산신이 뭐라고
Did the lions roll over when the kids died like that?
꼬맹이들이 그렇게 죽자 사자 굴렀는지
Sometimes I want to turn back time
가끔 시간을 돌리고 싶어
To you
너한테
There is no human woman I can never forget.
죽어라 못 잊는 인간 여자도 없고
There are no libations
신주도 없고
To the time when I didn't even have a younger brother.
동생도 없던 그 시절로
There's nothing to rely on
의지할 데라고는
We were everything to each other
우리 서로가 전부였는데
We are now Because they weren't those kids back then.
지금의 우리는 그때 그 어린애들이 아니니까
you forever I wish I couldn't open my eyes
네가 영원히 눈을 못 뜨면 좋겠다
Why are you suddenly speaking evil?
왜 갑자기 악담이야?
I'm the only one still living those days I'm pissed
나만 아직도 그 시절을 살고 있는 게 열받아서
you are helpless to me I'm going crazy because I want to see people living in anticipation.
네가 나한테 무기력하게 기대 사는 꼴을 보고 싶어서 미치겠어
You know that's not my style
그거 내 취향 아닌 거 알잖아
Yuna
연아
I'm giving you a chance now
나 지금 너한테 기회를 주고 있는 거야
Opportunity?
기회?
When I close my eyes They say they see more than they think
눈을 감으면 생각보다 많은 게 보인다며
You have to realize it yourself
네 스스로 깨달아야 돼
What should I see?
뭘 봐야 하는지
What did you miss when you opened your eyes?
눈을 뜨고 있을 때 놓친 게 뭔지
you saw it
넌 봤구나
red and white mask
홍백탈
You saw what was beyond that mask
그 탈 너머에 뭐가 있는지 넌 봤어
you saw it too
너도 봤어
What?
뭐?
Just one word
한마디만 하면
I can be on your side
난 네 편이 돼 줄 수도 있어
Or
아니면
I could be a worse enemy than him.
그놈보다 지독한 적이 될 수도 있고
Kid, let go of this.
아이씨, 이거 놔
answer me
대답해
- You are mine. - What's wrong with you?
- 넌 내 거라고 - 너 왜 이래?
I’m like this because I like you
네가 좋아서 이래
Wrong
틀렸어
you always
넌 항상
what you want Isn’t it only when you get your hands on it that your passion will go away?
네가 갖고 싶은 걸 손에 넣어야만 직성이 풀리지?
You just can't stand it, you
그걸 못 참는 것뿐이야, 넌
So
그래서
What is the answer?
대답은?
The fox
여우는
I never abandon a partner once I make one.
한 번 맺은 짝을 절대 버리지 않아
that's my answer
그게 내 답이야
Jaeyuya
재유야
Go and meet the monsters on the floor of Gyeongseong. Come and spread the word.
가서 경성 바닥 요괴들한테 소문 좀 내고 오너라
What do you mean?
뭐라고 말입니까?
Lee Yeon said she was blind.
이연이 눈멀었다고
Wow, how long has it been since this business was shut down?
와, 이게 얼마 만의 휴업이야?
go to the bathroom I need to push as hard as I can.
목욕탕 가서 실컷 때나 밀어야겠다
Is that so?
그럴까?
But is this okay?
근데 이래도 되는 걸까요?
leave the guest alone
손님 혼자 남겨 두고
It's the boss's order.
사장님 지시야
For us it's the law
우리한테는 그게 법이고
Ah, Mr.
아, 씨
That
저
Is there anyone outside?
밖에 아무도 없어?
Can you give me some water?
나 물 좀 줄래?
Yes, did you call me?
예, 부르셨습니까요?
Who are you? It's my first time hearing this voice.
누구야, 넌? 처음 듣는 목소리인데
It is called a stone that carries and chops firewood.
장작 패다 나르는 수돌이라고 합니다
Well, all the gisaengs went to the bathhouse.
이, 기생들이 전부 목욕탕에 간지라
Ah
아
Are you alone?
너 혼자야?
yes
예
give me your hand
나 손 좀
Where are you going?
어디 가시려고요?
Did you say Sudol?
수돌이라고 했지?
What are you doing here?
여기서 무슨 일 한다고?
He's a guy carrying firewood.
장작 나르는 놈입니다요
Yeah?
그래?
strange
이상하다
What do you mean?
뭐가 말입니까?
Your hands are clearly those of a knife holder.
네놈 손은 분명 칼잡이 손이거든
Just guess I think there are about 15 of them.
어림잡아 열댓 놈은 되는 것 같은데
What are you guys doing?
너희들 뭐 하는 놈들이냐?
As you go under the undressing group
네놈이 탈의파 밑으로 들어가면서
The monster that was caught and killed Do you know how many there are?
잡아 죽인 요괴가 몇이나 되는 줄 아냐?
I'm like that Do you look like someone who writes a diary?
내가 그런 걸 일기 쓰는 놈으로 보이냐?
A guy who can't even use his eyes has time to spare
눈도 못 쓰는 놈이 여유는
Did you know that foxes only hunt with their eyes?
여우가 사냥을 눈으로만 하는 줄 알아?
Oh, is it an amulet or something? Does it really have to be done in a place like this?
아, 액막인지 뭔지 꼭 이런 데서 해야 돼?
A lot of people step on it It has to be a road
사람이 많이 밟고 다니는 길이어야 돼요
Ah, why red beans?
아, 팥은 왜?
To chase away evil spirits
잡귀 쫓으려고
If you look at those rice cakes, you will be amazed.
그것들 떡 보면 환장하잖아
What time is it?
몇 시예요?
5 minutes before 12
12시 5분 전
It's almost on time
곧 정각이네
Please come in
들어오세요
Lee Yeon's hair
이연 님 머리카락
here
여기
Burn it at midnight
자정이 되면 태우세요
And without exception, north, south, east and west Sprinkle some alcohol...
그리고는 동서남북 빠짐없이 술을 뿌리고...
Baby, okay, tell me how many times
아이, 알았어, 몇 번을 말해
From now on, you and I will be alone.
이제부터 이랑 님 혼자예요
Please leave as soon as you finish.
끝나면 바로 자리 뜨세요
never until you arrive You cannot look back or speak.
도착할 때까지 절대 돌아보거나 말을 하시면 안 돼요
- You must never look at it. - Go
- 절대 보면 안 돼요 - 가
Jaeyuya
재유야
Our kite can't even use his ears I need to make it for you
우리 연이 귀도 못 쓰게 만들어 줘야겠다
yes
네
Ah, Mr.
아, 씨
Are you running away in a bad way?
꼴사납게 도망치는 거니?
Wait, five steps to the left.
잠깐, 왼쪽으로 다섯 걸음
One, two, three, four
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷
five
다섯
here
여기다
Now
자
Now it's fair darkness
이제 공평한 어둠이다
Oh no, it's not fun
아유, 재미없어
Are you going out?
외출이야?
It's a call from the grandmother of the undressing group.
탈의파 할멈 호출이야
I killed a person yesterday
어제 사람 하나 죽였거든
Leave Yeon alone
연이만 혼자 남겨 두고
Are you okay?
괜찮겠어?
Cook whatever you want
마음대로 요리해 봐
Let me see your skills.
어디 네 솜씨 좀 보자
Something on the way back If you feel like you're being chased, that's it.
돌아가는 길에 뭔가 쫓아오는 느낌이 들면 그것일 거예요
never look back
절대 돌아보지 마세요
never
절대
He's a lot more dangerous than I thought.
생각보다 훨씬 위험한 놈이다
I have a bad feeling
예감이 안 좋아
I'm going to catch up at this rate
이러다 따라잡히겠어
Hey, where are you going, boss?
어이, 어디 가세요, 두목?
yes? Let's go together
예? 같이 가요
Yes?
예?
what? Oh, why are you pretending not to know?
뭐야? 아, 왜 모르는 척을 해요?
specifications
시방
Now I'm pulling a rickshaw Are you doing this because you’re embarrassed, right now?
지금 나 인력거 끈다고 지금 창피해서 그러는 거야, 지금?
What, why aren't you talking?
뭐야, 왜 말을 안 하셔?
yes?
예?
I have to go, uh
가야 된다고, 어
Get in, then
타세요, 그럼
Taran
따란
What did you buy so much?
뭘 이렇게 많이 사셨어요?
It’s been a while since you smelled the sea, right? try one
바다 내음 맡은지 꽤 됐잖니? 하나 먹어 봐라
Does it taste good?
맛이 괜찮니?
It tastes much better than crucian carp.
붕어보다 훨 맛이 좋아요
Ah, but you
아, 근데 너
What is this all about?
이게 다 뭐야?
I want to give it as a gift There is a brother who came with me a few days ago.
선물하려고요 며칠 전에 같이 왔던 형제 있잖아요
Oh, you mean bro? Lee Yeon
아, 형 말이지? 이연 님
No, my brother.
아니, 동생이요
With this?
이랑?
His name is Rang.
이름이 랑이구나
Oh my goodness, Yeohee.
아서라, 여희야
don't go near
가까이 가지 마
Are you a bad guy?
나쁜 놈이에요?
very
아주
This kid has a lot of scars
상처가 많은 애야
Like you, one of your parents is human.
너처럼 부모 한쪽이 인간이거든
You know that too, right?
너도 알잖니?
Those who are neither humans nor monsters
인간도 요괴도 아닌 자들이
Which path do you end up taking?
결국 어떤 길을 가게 되는지
But I fell in love with it at first sight.
그렇지만 한눈에 반해 버린걸요
me
나
I'm going to fall in love with that guy
그 남자랑 사랑을 할 거예요
boss
사장님
Soon in Shanghai
조만간 상해에서
There's going to be a bomb
폭탄이 하나 들어올 거예요
I'll leave the back door open
뒷문 열어 놓을게
Oh, what's the password?
아, 암호는?
♪ Do-re-mi-re-do ♪
♪ 도레미레도 ♪
Take care of yourself
몸조심해
The boss too.
사장님도요
"Obok Goods Store"
"오복양품점"
Was the exorcism successful?
액막이 성공한 건가?
Now finally
이제 드디어
Our kite is alone
우리 연이 혼자네
Hey, what is this?
야, 이게 뭐냐?
Hey!
이야!
This is Jingogae, that It's selling like hot cakes
이게 진고개에서, 그 불티나게 팔려 나간다는
It's that castella.
그 카스테라구나
The bread is fluffy like cloud cookies, huh?
빵이 구름 과자처럼 푹신푹신하다, 어?
Hey Hongju! Why do you keep killing people?
야, 홍주! 너 왜 자꾸 사람을 죽이고 다녀?
Why can't I just kill him?
죽이면 왜 안 돼요?
They all die anyway
걔네 다 어차피 죽어
How can this guy who was once a mountain god!
한때는 산신이란 놈이 어찌!
Why are you the only one with me? Yeon also killed many soldiers.
왜 나만 갖고 그래? 연이도 군인 많이 죽였어
Why are you looking at him?
걔는 왜 봐줘?
Ah, that's Yeon in Myoyeonggak...
아, 그건 묘연각에 있는 연이가...
Hey!
야!
What is Yeoni?
연이가 뭐?
what?
뭐야?
Why don't you stop talking?
왜 말을 하다 말아?
The guy who killed people and came to get punishment talks a lot.
사람 죽이고 벌서러 온 놈이 말이 많다
Send it to cold ice hell
한빙지옥으로 보내
Oh, Hong Joo is also older. Let’s send it somewhere warmer.
아, 홍주도 나이가 있는데 좀 따뜻한 데 좀 보내 주고 그러지
Let's go
가요
Hey, this
야, 이거
Oh, that's right
아, 맞다
You know Muyoung is here, right?
무영이 온 거 알지?
uh?
어?
What do you mean? Is Muyoung alive?
그게 무슨 소리야? 무영이가 살아 있어?
Didn’t your grandmother save your life?
할멈이 살려 준 게 아니야?
Hongjoo
홍주야
Why did I raise Muyoung like my own child? Do you think it's made of stone?
내가 왜 자식처럼 키운 무영이를 돌로 만들었을 것 같니?
with my own hands
제 손으로
The mountain I ruled The thing that annihilated everything
제가 다스리던 산의 모든 것들을 몰살시킨 게
It's him
그놈이다
It can't be
그럴 리가
There’s no way Muyoung would do something like that.
무영이가 그런 짓을 할 리가 없잖아
I am like that
그런 내가
Would you have forgiven Muyoung?
무영이를 용서했겠니?
no
아니
Grandma would never...
할멈은 절대...
Take it away
데려가
alternative
대체
Who saved Muyoung?
누가 무영이를 살려 낸 거지?
For what?
뭘 위해서?
Langa
랑아
Shinju!
신주야!
Is there anyone?
아무도 없어?
uh?
어?
Rangi watch
랑이 시계
libation handkerchief
신주 손수건
Ah, Mr.
아, 씨
Oh, kinda!
아, 좀!
There's no one there!
거기 누구 없어!
Well, anyone is fine
누, 누구라도 좋으니까
please help me
제발 나 좀 도와줘
Huh?
어?
Please, please!
제발 좀, 제발!
please
제발
Who is it?
누구야?
runt?
꼬마?
Could you please read this letter?
이 편지 좀 읽어 줄래?
‘My younger brother and Shinju are dying’
'동생과 신주가 죽어가고 있습니다'
‘If you want to save the two of them’
'둘을 살리고 싶으면'
'At the eastern foot of Bukhansan Mountain 'Come to the hermitage'
'북한산 동쪽 기슭에 있는 암자로 오세요'
‘I’ll give you just one hour’
'딱 한 시간 드립니다'
'You know who I am, right?'
'내가 누군지는 알죠?'
Red and white mask, this bastard
홍백탈 이 새끼
Hey, kid
꼬, 꼬마야
help me
나 좀 도와줘
Give me a piggyback ride
업어 줘
uh
어
- This way - This way?
- 이쪽으로 - 이쪽?
Please save me!
살려 주세요!
Please save me! yes!
살려 주세요! 예!
Is there anyone? uh!
누구 없어? 어!
Please save me!
살려 주세요!
If you want to save me Would you have put it in something like this?
살려 줄 생각이면 이런 데다 집어넣었겠냐?
Hey, then what? They all look dead
아이, 그럼 뭐 다 죽게 생겼는데
I have to try something
뭐라도 해 봐야죠
Untie the line first
줄부터 풀어
It can't be done by force, it can't be done.
힘으로 안 돼, 안 돼
Lee Yeon will come to the rescue.
이연 님이 구하러 올 거예요
A guy who can't even see will come back easily.
눈도 안 보이는 놈이 잘도 오겠다
not the eyes Even if all my hands and feet are gone
눈이 아니라 손발이 다 없어져도
Lee Yeon will come to rescue Lee Rang.
이연 님은 이랑 님 구하러 올 거예요
I think you will too.
이랑 님도 그러실 거고
How do you know that?
그걸 네가 어떻게 알아?
you guys talk about me You can say whatever you know.
너희들이 나에 대해서 뭘 안다고 마음대로 지껄이는데
I know even though I can’t explain it.
설명은 못 해도 알아요
What a warm person you are.
이랑 님이 얼마나 따뜻한 분인데
I also bought a kimchi refrigerator.
김치냉장고도 사 주고
What on earth are you guys?
너희들 대체 정체가 뭐냐?
Is that a secret too?
그것도 비밀이야?
After living like everyone else for hundreds of years, suddenly
수백 년을 남처럼 살다가 갑자기
Come into my life and pretend to be nice
내 인생에 쳐들어와서 착한 척
Just pretend to be friendly, because it's disgusting.
친한 척 작작 좀 해, 역겨우니까
It seems like the water level is higher than before
아까보다 수위가 높아진 것 같아
Lee Yeon!
이연 님!
Thank you, kid.
고맙다, 꼬마야
Ah, the sound of the moktak
아, 목탁 소리
This way?
이쪽?
This is the stride length of an adult man.
성인 남자의 보폭이다
It's not a person, it's him.
사람이 아니야, 그놈이다
I'm deliberately shooting from a distance
일부러 비껴 쏘고 있어
You're playing with me
나를 가지고 노는 거야
As if chasing rabbits
토끼몰이라도 하듯
Damn it
젠장
Well, if it's not just the eyes
씨, 눈만 아니면
If it weren't for the eyes...
눈만 아니면...
you
너
You know me, right?
나 알지?
What are we doing?
우리 무슨 사이냐?
What on earth are you doing? Are you doing this to me?
도대체 무슨 사이길래 나한테 이러냐고!
받아
받아
뭔지 모르겠는데
뭔지 모르겠는데
내가 다 잘못했다
내가 다 잘못했다
나 너랑 싸울 생각 전혀 없어
나 너랑 싸울 생각 전혀 없어
그러니까
그러니까
랑이랑 신주만이라도
랑이랑 신주만이라도
제발
제발
피뢰침이다, 이 새끼야
피뢰침이다, 이 새끼야
아이씨, 어유, 씨
아이씨, 어유, 씨
좀만 더
좀만 더
- 뭐야? - That's enough, that's enough.
- 뭐야? - 됐어, 됐어
That's enough
됐어
What is that line, huh?
저 줄 뭐야, 어?
IC
아이씨
No, no, no.
안 돼, 안 돼, 안 돼
In this way, we both die
이러다 둘 다 죽어
What should I do?
어떡해?
Lee Rang!
이랑 님!
Lee Rang
이랑 님
Langa
랑아
Shinju!
신주야!
Give me back my eyes, okay?
내 눈 좀 돌려줘, 어?
Give me back my eyes, please!
내 눈 좀 돌려 달라고, 제발!
Find me
찾아 줘
my name
내 이름
Is this voice, that kid from earlier?
이 목소리, 아까 그 꼬마?
Could it be that you...
설마 네가...
Saetani
새타니
It's you, right?
네놈이지?
What took my eyes
내 눈 가져간 게
Give it to me
내놔
You're the one who broke your promise!
약속을 어긴 건 너야!
Find me
찾아 줘
my name
내 이름
Name?
이름?
How do I know that? Mr.
그딴 걸 내가 어떻게 알아? 씨
Die!
죽어 버려!
Where are you?
어디 있어?
Got it
잡았다
sound of bells
방울 소리
This sound, someday...
이, 이 소리 언젠가...
here
여기는
the forest I ruled
내가 다스리던 숲
The carp you just saved is
네가 방금 살려 준 잉어는
They are descendants of the owner of this pond.
이 연못 주인의 자손이다
I'll give you this as a reward
상으로 이걸 주마
What is this?
이게 뭐예요?
I'll grant you just one wish
딱 한 번 소원 들어줄게
What's your name?
이름이 뭐냐?
my name is
내 이름은
I...
나는...
tell me
말해
Tell me, what is your name?
말해, 네 이름이 뭐야?
Speak quickly!
빨리 말해!
tell me
말하라고
Sister, I'm hungry
언니, 나 배고프다
We're almost home, just hang in there
집 거의 다 왔어, 조금만 참아
Yeah
응
I'll take this kid
이 아이로 하겠습니다
Sister, I don’t want to go.
언니, 나 가기 싫어
I'm scared
무서워
our clothes
우리 옷
let's change it
바꿔 입자
don't go
가지 마
sister
언니
I want to go home
집에 가고 싶어
I'm thirsty
목말라
I don't want to die
죽기는 싫어
Mountain spirit
산신령님
Please save me
살려 주세요
I shouldn't have switched clothes with my brother.
동생이랑 옷을 바꿔 입지 말 걸 그랬어
I hate you
미워
My father too
아버지도
My younger brother too
동생도
Even the spirits
신령님도
I want to go home
집에 가고 싶어
I'm thirsty
목말라
I don't want to die
죽기 싫어
Mountain spirit
산신령님
Please save me
살려 주세요
please save me
제발 살려 주세요
Please, mountain spirit, spirit, please
제발, 산신령님, 신령님, 제발
Please save me, please
제발 살려 주세요, 제발
please help me
제발 도와주세요
Please help me, please help me
도와주세요, 도와주세요
Why didn't you come?
왜 안 왔어?
At that time I already
그때 난 이미
It wasn't a mountain god
산신이 아니었어
He abandoned his position as a mountain god.
산신의 직을 버렸다
to save a woman
한 여인을 구하기 위해
Now you can't save anyone
이제 넌 아무도 구할 수 없어
I'm sorry
미안하다
It's too late
너무 늦어서
my name is
내 이름은
I remembered your name
생각났어, 네 이름
my name?
내 이름?
your name is
네 이름은
It's the soothing of azalea.
진달래의 달래예요
Soothe it
달래야
Azalea
진달래
Soothe
달래
There's nothing holding you back now
이제 널 가두는 건 아무것도 없어
You don't have to live as Saetani anymore
더 이상 새타니로 살지 않아도 돼
It's not Saetani
새타니가 아니야
I
나는
Soothe
달래
yes
그래
You were scared, right?
무서웠지?
Dying alone there
저 안에서 혼자 죽어 가면서
In the next life
다음 생에는
Born as an ordinary child
평범한 아이로 태어나서
Shaman or Saetani
무당이든 새타니든
Let's not live as anyone else's tool
그 누구의 도구로도 살지 말자
I had a hard time
고생했다
Living in this small body
이 작은 몸으로 사느라
wish
소원
Thanks for listening
들어줘서 고마워
My younger brother
동생은
It's at the western well.
서쪽 우물에 있어
Shinjuya
신주야
yes
예
- We're all here, we're all here - Lee Yeon
- 다 왔다, 다 왔다 - 이연 님
Shinju!
신주야!
are you okay?
괜찮아?
What about Rangi?
랑이는?
It hasn't come out yet
아직 못 나왔어
The grandmother saved Muyoung’s life You mean no?
할멈이 무영이를 살려 준 게 아니란 말이지?
But Muyoung and Yeoni
헌데 무영이랑 연이가
He appeared in Gyeongseong on the same day.
같은 날 경성에 나타났고
you guys
너희들
What is it?
정체가 뭐냐?
Lang, can you recognize me?
랑아, 나 알아볼 수 있겠어?
Ah, thank goodness
아, 다행이다
Playing with Yeon It's still fun
연이랑 노는 건 여전히 재미있단 말이야
Yuna
연아
You're forever stuck in the past
넌 영원히 과거에 갇혀서
everything you care about You'll see me dying
네가 아끼는 모든 게 죽어 가는 걸 보게 될 거야
that day
그날
It's a first for me too There is a thing called a bucket list.
내게도 처음 버킷 리스트라는 게 생겼다
Can you move your legs?
다리 움직일 수 있겠어?
Even if I leave
내가 떠나도
I wish there was someone next to Rang.
랑이 옆에 누군가 있어 주면 좋겠다
at least
적어도
In the era in which they live, things like red and white masks
쟤들이 살아갈 시대에 홍백탈 같은 거
I will never leave you alive
절대 살려 두지 않을 거야
red and white mask
홍백탈
Who are you?
누구냐?
He knows me, right?
놈은 날 알지?
- Shhh - You guys already
- 쉿 - 너희들은 이미
You guys are in a dog fight pulled me in
너희들 개싸움에 날 끌어들였어
If you measure the length and width of a corpse,
시체의 가로세로를 재면은
It is the treasure that even the dead come back to life.
죽은 자도 살아난다는 그 보물이에요
Baby
아가야
- Let’s hit him and knock him out. - Hey, hey, hey, it's wet.
- 때려서 기절시키자 - 야, 야, 야, 축축해
Is this person?
얘 사람 맞아?
Isn’t this a disguised monster?
둔갑한 요괴 아니야?
What is your ideal type?
이상형은?
A guy stronger than me
나보다 강한 놈
Why did you come to this era?
왜 이 시대에 왔니?
I'm fake?
내가 가짜라고?
One of the two with my own hands I might have to kill him.
내 손으로 둘 중 하나를 죽여야 할지도 모르겠다
don't go, please
가지 마, 제발